{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Wanda Maximoff","incorrectAnswers":["Valkyrie","Carol Danvers","The Ancient One"],"question":"Elizabeth Olsen plays the role of which character in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Power and the Glory","incorrectAnswers":["The Remains of the Day","Post Office","Nine Stories"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'The Whiskey Priest'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Badminton","Cycling","Basketball"],"question":"With which sport is Steffi Graf associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Hobbit","incorrectAnswers":["Charlotte's Web","Alice's Adventures in Wonderland","Bluebeard"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'In a hole in the ground there lived a hobbit.'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Uma Thurman","incorrectAnswers":["Penélope Cruz","Kirsten Dunst","Kristin Scott Thomas"],"question":"Which actress has appeared in both Batman & Robin and Kill Bill Volume 1?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Hiroshima","incorrectAnswers":["Tokyo","Osaka","Nagasaki"],"question":"On What Japanese City Was The First Atomic Bomb Dropped?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Azerbaijan","incorrectAnswers":["Kyrgyzstan","Tajikistan","Uzbekistan"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Russia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Frankenfood","incorrectAnswers":["Finifugal","Macrosmatic","Poppycock"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'genetically modified food'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Boxing","incorrectAnswers":["Golf","Tennis","Soccer"],"question":"In the film 'Million Dollar Baby', what sport does the protagonist pursue?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Bleach","incorrectAnswers":["Chloroform","QuickSilver","Caustic soda"],"question":"What is the common name for sodium hypochlorite?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"La Paz","incorrectAnswers":["Sucre","Santiago","Bogota"],"question":"What is the capital of Bolivia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Voltaire","incorrectAnswers":["Baruch Spinoza","Epictetus","Socrates"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'If God did not exist, it would be necessary to invent Him'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The eyeball","incorrectAnswers":["The ear","The brain","The skeleton"],"question":"What part of the body is the sclera a part of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Copenhagen","incorrectAnswers":["Aarhus","Aalborg","Roskilde"],"question":"What is the capital of Denmark?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"43","incorrectAnswers":["48","51","57"],"question":"How old was John F. Kennedy when he became president?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A recruit in Vietnam finds himself caught in a battle of wills between two sergeants.","incorrectAnswers":["A family of undercover superheroes are forced into action to save the world.","A noble family becomes embroiled in a war for control over the galaxy's most valuable asset.","A slacker seeks restitution for a rug ruined by debt collectors."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Platoon?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Blackpink","incorrectAnswers":["GOT7","T-ara","Super Junior"],"question":"Which South Korean girl group released the extended play 'Kill This Love'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Carmen Miranda","incorrectAnswers":["Gloria Estefan","Celia Cruz","Jennifer Lopez"],"question":"Which Latin music legend is known for her signature fruity hat?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Georgia","incorrectAnswers":["Vietnam","South Sudan","Albania"],"question":"Tbilisi is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jason Bateman","incorrectAnswers":["Javier Bardem","Colin Firth","Tim Roth"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including DodgeBall: A True Underdog Story and Up in the Air?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cincinnati Reds","incorrectAnswers":["Cincinnati Packers","Cincinnati Real","Cincinnati Suns"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in Cincinnati?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Fusilli","incorrectAnswers":["Penne","Bavette","Strozzapreti"],"question":"Which pasta's name means 'rifles'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"William the Conqueror","incorrectAnswers":["Rollo the Viking","Charlemagne","Alfred the Great"],"question":"Who was the English king that was crowned in Westminster Abbey in 1066?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A young F.B.I. cadet must receive the help of a cannibal to help catch another serial killer.","incorrectAnswers":["A tramp who has fallen in love with a blind flower girl saves money to help her medically.","Follows the rise and fall of a stock-broker living the high life.","A former neo-nazi tries to prevent his brother from going down the same path that he did."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The Silence of the Lambs?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"animal diseases","incorrectAnswers":["a synonym of Pulmonology","cells","the climate"],"question":"What is Zoopathology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Egypt","Italy","China"],"question":"In which country would you find the Taj Mahal?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Edgar Allan Poe","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Nathaniel Hawthorne","Mario Puzo"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Murders in the Rue Morgue'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Louise Fletcher","incorrectAnswers":["Isabelle Adjani","Ann-Margret","Glenda Jackson"],"question":"Who won the 1975 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Nurse Mildred Ratched in One Flew over the Cuckoo's Nest?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Irving Berlin","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen Sondheim","Andrew Lloyd Webber","George Gershwin"],"question":"Who Wrote The Musical \"There's No Business Like Show Business\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Madrid ","incorrectAnswers":["Lisbon","Paris","Rome"],"question":"Which European capital city stands on the Manzanares River?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Oliver Cromwell","incorrectAnswers":["Henry VIII","Francis Drake","Elizabeth I"],"question":"Who banned Christmas in Britain in 1647?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1964","incorrectAnswers":["1955","1970","1969"],"question":"In what year did the U.S. begin direct military involvement in Vietnam?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"11 Pipers Piping","incorrectAnswers":["11 Drummers Drumming","11 Lords a Leaping","11 Maids a Milking"],"question":"What did 'my true love give to me' on the eleventh day of Christmas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","Italy","Chile"],"question":"Which country hosted the 1938 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Lenin","incorrectAnswers":["St. Paul","Stalin","Gorbachev"],"question":"Which influential historical person was leader of the Russian Revolution and new Communist regime from 1917 to 1924?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Oliver Cromwell","incorrectAnswers":["Henry VIII","Charles I","Lord Byron"],"question":"Who was the leader of the Parliamentary forces during the English Civil War?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Adrien Brody","incorrectAnswers":["Nicolas Cage","Michael Caine","Daniel Day-Lewis"],"question":"Who won the 2002 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Wladyslaw Szpilman in The Pianist?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Netherlands","incorrectAnswers":["Croatia","Finland","Spain"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Rotterdam?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kylie Minogue","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Mika","Hikaru Utada"],"question":"Which singer released the song 'Spinning Around'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Hurt\" by Nine Inch Nails","incorrectAnswers":["\"Hooked on a Feeling\" by B.J. Thomas","\"Old Man\" by Neil Young","\"I'll Make a Man Out of You\" by Donny Osmond"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"I hurt myself today / To see if I still feel / I focus on the pain / The only thing that's real...\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"No worries","incorrectAnswers":["Stay strong","Keep trying","You win some you loose some"],"question":"What is the meaning of the Swahili phrase \"Hakuna Matata\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Denmark","incorrectAnswers":["Norway","Sweden","Finland"],"question":"From what country did the U.S. buy the Virgin Islands?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Squid-like","incorrectAnswers":["Pens","homemade","Priest-chokers"],"question":"The pasta calamarata has what meaning in Italian?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Reichstag","incorrectAnswers":["The Brandenburg Gate","Charlottenburg Palace","The Berlin Wall"],"question":"Which building in Berlin was burned down In 1933?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Bartolomeu Dias ","incorrectAnswers":["Amerigo Vespucci","Ferdinand Magellan","Francis Drake"],"question":"Who Accidently Sailed Around The Cape Of Good Hope In 1488?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Iwo Jima","incorrectAnswers":["Okinawa","Guam","Saipan"],"question":"Which island was the scene of the famous flag-raising during World War II and is depicted in the US Marine Corps War Memorial statue?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Roasted","incorrectAnswers":["Fried","Steamed","Boiled"],"question":"How is Peking duck prepared?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Dom Perignon","incorrectAnswers":["Veuve Clicquot","Moet and Chandon","Taittinger"],"question":"What is the name of the champagne named after a Benedictine monk?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A sounder","incorrectAnswers":["A shoal","A flock","A sedge"],"question":"What is the word for a group of boars?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Abraham Lincoln","incorrectAnswers":["John Adams","Thomas Jefferson","Andrew Johnson"],"question":"Which president signed the Emancipation Proclamation?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Four","incorrectAnswers":["One","Two","Three"],"question":"How many chambers does the human heart have?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Switzerland","incorrectAnswers":["Liechtenstein","Slovenia","San Marino"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Germany?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Columbus Blue Jackets","incorrectAnswers":["Columbus Mavericks","Columbus Predators","Columbus Whitesox"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in Columbus?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"James Stewart","incorrectAnswers":["Anthony Hopkins","Peter Lorre","Peter Finch"],"question":"Which actor played the role of George Bailey in It's A Wonderful Life?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Dushanbe","incorrectAnswers":["Moscow","Vilnius","Antananarivo"],"question":"What is the capital city of Tajikistan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Frances McDormand","incorrectAnswers":["Brenda Blethyn","Diane Keaton","Kristin Scott Thomas"],"question":"Who won the 1996 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Marge Gunderson in Fargo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Baseball","incorrectAnswers":["Basketball","American Football","Soccer"],"question":"With which sport is Babe Ruth associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sumida River","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow River","Kiso River","Pearl River"],"question":"Which river runs through Tokyo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mr. Bean","incorrectAnswers":["Teddy Ruxpin","Paddington Bear","Cornelius Fudge"],"question":"What is the name of the Rowan Atkinson character who calls his teddy bear and best friend \"Teddy\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A Chinese philosopher. ","incorrectAnswers":["Confirmed the theory that Earth revolves around The Sun.","Philosopher and mathematician who famously said “I think, therefore I am.”","Prophet of Islam."],"question":"Which of the following describes Mencius?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kuala Lumpur","incorrectAnswers":["Yangon","Suwon","Phnom Penh"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Malaysia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lithuania","incorrectAnswers":["Israel","Saudi Arabia","Sweden"],"question":"Which of these countries has red on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dutch Golden Age","incorrectAnswers":["Neoclassicism","Dutch and Flemish Renaissance","Fauvism"],"question":"The painting \"Girl with a Pearl Earring\" by ‎‎Johannes Vermeer is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"everything","incorrectAnswers":["cancer","race","the interrelationship between an organism's physical functioning and its environment"],"question":"What is Omnology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I am big! It's the pictures that got small.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Life is a banquet, and most poor suckers are starving to death!\"","\"I am a golden god!\"","\"A boy's best friend is his mother.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Sunset Blvd.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"South America","incorrectAnswers":["Oceania","Europe","Asia"],"question":"The country of Suriname is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Norse","incorrectAnswers":["Latin","Arabic","Greek"],"question":"From which language does the word 'ransack' come from?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tonga","incorrectAnswers":["The USA","New Zealand","North Korea"],"question":"Which country altered it's timezone in order to be the first to see in the year 2000?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"John Adams","incorrectAnswers":["Herbert Hoover","Calvin Coolidge","Ulysses S. Grant"],"question":"Who was the 2nd president of the USA, in term during the period 1797–1801?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"New York","incorrectAnswers":["Chicago","Paris","London"],"question":"In 'Home Alone 2' which city was Kevin lost in?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jules Verne","incorrectAnswers":["Victor Hugo","Alphonse Daudet","Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Michael Strogoff'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ukraine","incorrectAnswers":["Kyrgyzstan","Belarus","Georgia"],"question":"Odessa is a city in which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Comb","incorrectAnswers":["Pliers","Scissor","Razor"],"question":"What is the name of the toothed object commonly used to straighten hair?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Al Capone","incorrectAnswers":["Jesus","John F Kennedy","Mother Theresa"],"question":"Who said 'public service is my motto'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Edward Jenner","incorrectAnswers":["Alexander Fleming","Louis Pasteur","Jonas Salk"],"question":"Who developed the first successful vaccine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Winter Wonderland","incorrectAnswers":["Jingle Bells","Driving Home For Christmas","Silent Night"],"question":"In which famous Christmas Song is a snowman pretended to be \"Parsons Brown\"?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Baseball","Athletics","Motorsports"],"question":"Which sport is played at The Billie Jean King Cup?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Eight ","incorrectAnswers":["Two","Four","Sixteen"],"question":"How many standard bottles of wine are in a Methuselah? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jack Nicholson","incorrectAnswers":["Dwayne Johnson","Shah Rukh Khan","Gérard Depardieu"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Batman and One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oman","incorrectAnswers":["Jordan","Israel","Kuwait"],"question":"In which country is the city of Muscat?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kevin Bacon","incorrectAnswers":["Richard Harris","Anthony Quinn","Hugo Weaving"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including The Following and Apollo 13?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Earwig","incorrectAnswers":["Ant","Praying Mantis","Woodlouse"],"question":"Which Insect Has A Pair Of Prominent Pincers At The Tip Of It's Abdomen?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Us and Them'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Singapore Sling ","incorrectAnswers":["Mojito","Daiqiri","Manhattan"],"question":"Which Cocktail Was Invented At The Raffles Hotel?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Catherine the Great","incorrectAnswers":["Mary Wollstonecraft","Queen Elizabeth I","Anne Boleyn"],"question":"Which famous female ruler came to power in a 1762 coup against her husband?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Philadelphia 76ers","incorrectAnswers":["Philadelphia Inter","Philadelphia Lions","Philadelphia Whitecaps"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Philadelphia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Nikolai Gogol","incorrectAnswers":["Virginia Woolf","Alexander Pushkin","Ayn Rand"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Taras Bulba'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Britney Spears","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Alanis Morissette","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter, dancer and actress released the studio album 'Oops!… I Did It Again'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cuba","incorrectAnswers":["Jamaica","Haiti","Dominican Republic"],"question":"In Which Country Will You Find The Bay Of Pigs?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Victoria","incorrectAnswers":["Saint George's","Quito","Managua"],"question":"What is the capital city of Seychelles?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"An Embolism","incorrectAnswers":["An Aneurysm","A Hemorrhage","A Stroke"],"question":"In medical terms, what is the name of a condition in which a blood vessel gets blocked by an air bubble moving through the bloodstream?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Spaghetti","incorrectAnswers":["Fettuccine","Ravioli","Linguine"],"question":"Which pasta's name means 'Little twine'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Metallica","incorrectAnswers":["Alice Cooper","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American heavy metal band released the studio album 'Kill 'Em All'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Jenny","incorrectAnswers":["A Cow","A Sow","A Hembra"],"question":"A female mule is known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Pressure","incorrectAnswers":["Volume","Luminescence","Temperature"],"question":"According to Boyle's Law, what increases when a gas is compressed to half its size?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Gold","Yellow","Blue"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Japan?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Joanne Kathleen","incorrectAnswers":["Julia Kathleen","Joanne Katherine","Julia Katherine"],"question":"What do the initials \"JK\" stand for in the name \"JK Rowling\", Author of the \"Harry Potter\" books?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Pele","incorrectAnswers":["Ronaldinho","Neymar","Socrates"],"question":"Who is 'Edson Arantes do Nascimento' better known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Charles I","incorrectAnswers":["Henry VIII","Edward VII","Charles II"],"question":"Which English king was executed in 1649?","difficulty":"hard"},